这首真的算是家喻户晓
is the one that really circulated in a large way.
轰动了全国  是吧?
It was a national hit, then?
确实轰动了全国  可以这么说
It was a national hit, that's a good way to put it.
对该案子的好奇
It's really the interest in the case,
以及在那个时候  十九世纪二十年代
plus the fact that there was at that time, the 1820s,
有一股歌唱狂潮
a strong popular singing tradition -
人们就爱唱歌  为休闲  为娱乐
people singing for themselves, for recreation, for fun -
然后  确实引起了轰动  好了  我们试着唱一下吧
that meant things like this were a hit. Well, let's have a sing.
好的  预备
Yes, let's.
# 来吧  冲动无知的年轻人 #
# Come, all you thoughtless young men #
# 听听我的忠告 #
# A warning take by me #
# 想想我将被吊死在树上的不幸 #
# And think upon my unhappy fate to be hanged upon the tree #
# 我叫威廉・科德 #
# My name is William Corder #
# 我承认犯了罪 #
# To you I do declare #
# 我杀了玛利亚・马滕 #
# I courted Maria Marten #
# 美丽可爱的姑娘 #
# Most beautiful and fair. #
假如1928年我在伦敦做服务员
Supposing I was a servant in London in 1928
如果我想学这首歌的话  我该怎么做
and I wanted to learn this song, how would I go about doing it?
很可能你会从街边民谣歌手
The most likely way you would learn it
口中知道这首歌
is from a street ballad singer.
当时有很多这样的歌手
There were hundreds of these people,
甚至19世纪中期还有很多
even in the mid-19th century in London.
他们不仅仅是卖艺的
They're not just buskers,
他们在唱的同时  还卖这些曲子
because they would both sing and sell the ballad at the same time,
这样的话  你就会学会这些调子
and that's the way you would learn the tune.
有很多人都围在他们身边
We have accounts of large crowds of people standing
听这些歌
listening to ballad singers.
这样确实不错
It's a really good idea,
因为如果每个伦敦市民都唱的话
because if everybody across Britain is singing this,
就像是一个严重警告  是不是
it's like a massive public safety warning, isn't it,
告诉人们  不要杀人灭口  埋在谷仓
saying "Don't go murdering ladies and burying them in barns.
对你没有好处的  你会被处死
"It will be bad for you. You will die".
是啊  可以这么说
Yes! You can look at it that way,
或者  可以这样认为  当时的报纸
or you can look at it on the way that the popular press
既感到高兴  又不愿对这种
both delights in and takes a sort of distanced view
血淋淋的事情进行过多报道
of gory happenings and so on.
所以既有振奋人心的部分  又是一种警告
There's both the fascination and the warning element in there.
两种态度都很强烈
They're both quite strong.
但是歌曲所表达的  就是  不要杀人  对吧
The lesson of the song is, though, don't do it, isn't it?
尽管是一种愉悦感
Although they are taking a bit of pleasure
对那具血肉模糊的尸体
in the "bleeding, mangled body".
我们再唱一下"血肉模糊"吧?  好  我还挺喜欢那首的
Shall we try the "bleeding, mangled" verse? Yeah, I like that one.
#毫无顾忌  以为不会有危险#
# With heart so light she thought no harm #
#于是她就去见了他#
# To meet him she did go #
#在谷仓杀了她  看着她倒下#
# He murdered her all in the barn and laid her body low #
#腥风血雨之后#
# And after the horrible deed was done #
#她直直地躺在了血泊中#
# She lay weltering in her gore #
#他把她血肉模糊的尸体埋在了#
# Her bleeding, mangled body he buried #
#谷仓红色的地板下#
# Beneath the red barn floor. #
真是一种荒唐的恐怖
That's ridiculously ghoulish!
血淋淋的  尸体  扭曲  恶
The blood, the body, the mangling, ugh!
毕竟杀人不是一件光彩的事  细节部分让人欲罢不能
Murder is not a nice thing, and this is relishing in that detail.
为天使之声干杯
The voice of an angel.
情节剧  抨击和民谣
Melodramas and broadsides and ballads
让波尔斯特德臭名昭著
had made Polstead infamous.
游客专为谋杀案而来  迫切想要参观这个村子
Murder tourists arrived, wanting to visit the village
来看看红谷仓  甚至想摸一下玛利亚的坟墓
to see the red barn, and even to touch the grave of poor Maria.
这块板子上写着  玛利亚・马滕就葬在附近
This board here tells us that Maria Marten is buried nearby.
她那时才年满25岁
She was aged just 25 years.
我们没法见到她真正的墓碑
We can't see her actual gravestone
早就被人切成一片一片  做成纪念品了
because it was chipped to pieces by souvenir hunters,
现在连渣都找不到
and there isn't a trace of it left.
在犯罪故事中
As in many a crime story,
我们对红谷仓谋杀案中最感兴趣的是
the murder in the red barn shows that we are more interested
凶手的性格和品行
in the character and the deeds of the murderer
而不是受害者
than those of the victim.
威廉・科德谋杀案发生后  兴起了一个
William Corder's crime created a weird industry
叫凶杀案纪念品的新兴产业
in what we might call murder souvenirs.
只要有钱
Anyone who had the cash
就可以买到红谷仓的陶瓷制品
could buy one of these ceramic models of the red barn,
拿回家  放在壁炉台
take it home and have it on your own mantelpiece.
更离谱的是
Slightly more exclusive
还有用红谷仓大梁木制成的小工艺品
were knick-knacks made out of the timbers of the red barn itself.
这是一个鞋状的鼻烟盒
This is a little snuffbox in the shape of a shoe.
和谋杀关系越近的纪念品  价格就越高
The items associated with the crime were more valuable.
这是真的手枪  他当时作案的工具
These were the actual pistols. These are what he used to shoot her.
恐怖性已经上升到了一个层次
Ascending up the scale of gruesomeness,
这本书写的是威廉・科德
this is a book about William Corder,
是由泰晤士报的记者写的
written by a journalist from The Times.
别以为这只是普通的一本书  打开封面
You'd think it was just a book, until you open up the cover
就会发现  皮质的封面
and you read that the leather binding is made
是用凶手的皮肤制成的
from the skin of the murderer,
一名萨福克的外科医生
taken from his body and tanned by a surgeon
从他尸体上取下晒干制成
from the Suffolk Hospital.
最让你意想不到的  头皮发麻的
But top of the tree, absolutely most gruesome of all,
是这个  威廉・科德的头的背部
this is the back of William Corder's head.
这是他的头皮
It's the skin from his scalp.
几根头发还在上面
You can see on it the little hairs,
这里  是凶手的耳朵
and just over here is the murderer's ear.
颅相学家对他的头很感兴趣
Phrenologists were also keen to study Corder's head,
因为他们觉得上面坑坑洼洼的肿块
because they thought the lumps and bumps on it
跟他行凶有一定的联系
represented the homicidal aspects of his personality.
这是什么
What is this?
这是威廉・科德的立体半身相
This is a full 3-D bust of William Corder, taken from death.
看上去确实很阴森
It does bear some of the grim signs
想到他被勒窒息而死
of his death by strangulation and asphyxiation.
你从前面看
If you look at the front
可以看到他嘴唇和鼻子是肿胀的
where you can see the lips and the nose are swollen,
是因为当时血管爆裂
that is where all the blood vessels are bursting in his face.
这里  可以看到死前的挣扎
Here, you can see someone struggling through death.
那威廉・科德的尸体后来怎么处理的
Tell me what happened to William Corder's body afterwards.
他吊在那里差不多有一个小时
He would have probably been left to hang for about an hour,
只是为了确保他死了
just to make sure he was certainly dead.
后来就把他尸体运到了前郡政厅
Then he would have been taken down to the Shire Hall,
在那里  他被公开解剖
where basically, they would have publicly anatomised him.
他的尸体竟然就这样
So I'm getting an impression of this dead body
运到前郡政厅
being brought into the Shire Hall over there,
大庭广众之下  一大群的人围着观察  是啊
and swarms of people coming to examine it, all in public? Yes.
其实  他被绞刑的那天
Presumably, it would have been
算是很隆重的一天
the same sort of grand day out as the execution.
如果有人错过了
If you missed the execution,
就过来看他四分五裂的尸体
you could go along and watch the body being cut up.
事实上
It was, in essence,
这是跟著名暴徒近距离接触的大好机会
your chance to see a celebrity of the nefarious sort.
可不可以说他促进了
Would you say that he has contributed
当地的旅游业?  完全正确
to the local tourist industry? Absolutely.
由于之前他在这儿陈列了一百多年
Since he's been on display here for the last hundred years,
每个人来了都要问
people come in every day saying,
“你有没有那本封面是皮肤的书”
"Have you still got the book bound in skin?
“你有没有把皮肤扯下来”  等等
"Have you got the bit of skin?" etc.
实话说
And to be honest,
波尔斯特德的狂热者
the likes of the community of Polstead
还庆祝威廉・科德被绞刑
still celebrate the story of William Corder
还有红房子谋杀案
and the murder in the red barn.
"庆祝当地的杀人犯"  听着还真搞笑
It's really funny to hear you saying "We celebrate our local murderer"!
我觉得是因为这个故事经历了漫长的变迁
I think it's because the story has gone under so many transitions
几乎变成了传说  像个故事一样
to become basically so fabricated that it is a story.
我觉得我们庆祝的是一个故事
And I think we're celebrating the story,
而不是罪行的恶劣
as opposed to the reality of the nastiness of the crime.
而且这跟戏剧一样极具娱乐性
And it has all the bearings of a great, entertaining play.
玛利亚・马滕的故事说明了
The tale of Maria Marten showed
萨福克郡的谋杀
how a crime of passion in rural Suffolk
变成了全国的娱乐的过程
could become a national source of entertainment.
这使得威廉・科德
It elevated William Corder
一举成为那个世纪最臭名昭著的凶手
into one of the most notorious murderers of the century.
20年后  一个女杀人犯
20 years later, it would be a famous murderess
同样吸引住了公众的眼球
who would similarly enthral the public.
这个美貌但冷血的女人
This attractive and apparently cold-hearted woman
由于柏孟塞谋杀案
became infamous for her part
而声名狼藉
in the crime known as the Bermondsey Horror.
玛利亚・曼宁
Maria Manning was living
住在伦敦南部柏孟塞米尼弗3号
at No.3, Miniver Place, Bermondsey, South London,
他的丈夫叫弗雷德里克
with her husband, Frederick.
故事发生在1849年
The year was 1849.
弗雷德里克和玛利亚・曼宁
Frederick and Maria Manning
是即将步入30的新婚夫妇
were a newly married couple in their late twenties.
弗雷德里克是铁路护卫工
Frederick had been a guard on the railways,
后来经商破了产
and then he had failed in business as a publican
于是失业在家
and now he was unemployed.
他的妻子玛利亚  极具异国情调
His wife, Maria, was much more exotic.
她是瑞士人  花季青春当了一个女佣
She was Swiss, and she had lived the high life as a lady's maid.
身在异国他乡  住在豪宅里
She had travelled abroad and stayed in stately homes.
然而她后来也落难了
But she too had fallen on hard times.
依靠做裁缝的微薄收入度日
Now she was making ends meet as a dressmaker.
她还住在米尼弗的时候
A frequent visitor to the Mannings' house in Miniver Place
帕特里克・奥科诺尔经常来看他  他在海关工作
was Patrick O'Connor. He worked for the Customs,
据说他很富裕
and he was rumoured to be a very wealthy man.
三个人的关系始终非常古怪
The three of them certainly had a curious relationship.
事实上  这是个丑闻  相当于三角恋
In fact, it was scandalous. This was almost certainly a love triangle.
8月9日  星期四那天  帕特里克・奥科诺尔跟朋友说
On Thursday, 9th August, Patrick O'Connor told friends
曼宁邀请他晚上去做客
that he had been invited to have dinner with the Mannings.
那天之后  再也没有人见过他
This was the last time he was seen alive.
也就是那天晚上  他被杀害了
Sometime during that evening, he was ruthlessly killed.
玛利亚用他的钥匙进入了他的住处
Then, using his keys, Maria went to his lodgings
偷走了他的财务  包括股票
and stole his valuables, including his stock and share certificates.
四天后
Four days later,
有人向伦敦警察厅报案说奥科诺尔失踪
O'Connor was reported missing to a now centralised Metropolitan Police.
8月17日  周五那天
On Friday the 17th of August,
两名巡警进入了米尼弗3号
two police constables got access to 3 Miniver Place.
他们是K队的巴尔内斯警员
They were PC Barnes of the K Division
M队的伯森警员  都来自伦敦警察厅
and PC Burson of the M Division, both for the Metropolitan Police.
在房子里  他们发现一团糟
Inside the house, they found a state of confusion.
所有的家具都不在了
Whatever furniture had been here had disappeared
曼宁夫妇也不见了
and the Mannings were gone.
巡警汇报说  巢还在
The constables reported back that the nest were still here
但是鸟已经飞了
but the birds had flown.
然后他们就去搜厨房
Their search then took them into the back kitchen.
两名巡警好眼力
The two police constables had eagle eyes.
在厨房
In the kitchen,
他们发现壁炉前地板上的石板是松的
they noticed that one of the flagstones was loose near the hearth.
他们迅速挪开  发现了奥科诺尔
They soon had it up and there was O'Connor.
他全身赤裸地被捆绑着扔在石灰堆里
He was naked, he's been trussed up, he'd been tossed in quicklime
全身发青
and his dead body was now blue.
于是对逃犯的追捕开始了
The hunt for the murderers was now on,
伦敦警察厅新成立的分局着手此案
led by the newly formed detective branch of the Metropolitan Police
由查尔斯・菲尔德巡官负责
under inspector Charles Field.
柏孟塞谋杀案是他们证明自己实力的一起案件
The Bermondsey horror was a chance for them to prove themselves.
首先  他们得找到曼宁夫妇
First, Field's men had to track the Mannings down.
但是  他们能去哪里了呢
But where were they?
曼宁夫妇分开了  逃往两个不同的地方
The Mannings had split up and run in different directions.
玛利亚带着偷来的财产先走一步
It seems that Maria had gone off first without
而对丈夫的去向一无所知
the knowledge of her husband, but with the couple's stolen wealth.
曼宁夫妇抢了奥科诺尔的财产并且杀了他
The Mannings had robbed O'Connor and they'd killed him,
最重要的是  玛利亚欺骗了他的丈夫
and on top of that, Maria had double-crossed her husband.
玛利亚逃向了北部的苏格兰
Maria fled north to Scotland
而倒霉的弗雷德里克上了一艘去海峡群岛的轮船
while the hapless Fredrick caught a steamer to the Channel Islands.
为了了解侦探最终如何抓住曼宁夫妇
To discover more about how the detectives were able to trace
我再次和罗莎琳德・克罗恩在伦敦南部相会
the Mannings, I met up again with Rosalind Crone in south London.
1811年  拉特克利夫公里路谋杀案发生时
In 1811, when we have the Ratcliff Highway murders,
官方相当不给力
there's a slightly chaotic response from the authorities
但是曼宁夫妇谋杀案发生时  情况就不同了是吧?
but things are very different by the times of the Mannings, aren't they?
是啊    后来是一个综合的巡查系统
Yes. What we see is a much more joined-up system of policing,
更重要的是  由新的侦探队伍加入进来了
but more significantly they're joined by a new detective force.
后来  1829年伦敦警察厅的成立是为了
Now, the Metropolitan Police force in 1829 are meant to be very much
防止犯罪行为
a preventing crime force,
so they patrol beats and keep a watch over people and property.
1842年成立的侦探小组  是为了侦查破案
The detective force, founded in 1842, is meant to detect crime.
目的上有所不同
It's a slightly different function.
但他们当时都是小型的
But they're only a small office at this stage -
在苏格兰场  大概只有8个人
about eight man in total in their office in Scotland Yard.
所以申请新的侦探小组  最后也通过了
So we've got this new detective squad and they're allowed, actually,
第一次就去追捕罪犯
to go after the criminals for the first time.
他们后来是怎么抓住玛利亚的呢?
How did they actually catch Maria?
首先  去房子里侦察的巡佐
First of all, the detective sergeant who's sent out to have a
想办法找到了当时送玛利亚去车站
look at the house, is able to track down the cab driver who takes
的出租车司机
Maria to the station.